Eugene Gluhotorenko

Senior Software Engineer, Technical Lead

• Leiden, Netherlands

e.gluhotorenko@gmail.com

★ http://e.gluhotorenko.com

gevgeny

in eugene gluhotorenko

PROFILE

Solid software engineer with 10+ years of experience in delivering various web products. Expert in frontend with desktop and backend development background. Passionate about programming, data visualization, rich web apps. I spend most of my spare time reading pop science books, doing sport, traveling and developing open source.

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, Swift, MobX, Node.js, Jest, PixiJS, HTML, CSS, Git and a lot of other libraries and tools.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

EPO / SaM Solutions | From Jan 2021

TypeScript React MobX Node.js BaseWeb

- Porting monolithic app to micro frontend architecture. Made the patent document viewer portable in order to provide access to the tool for other projects in the company.
- Rebuilding existing app features to provide better performance in rendering of contentheavy pages. Rewrote the annotation viewer from SVG to Canvas, which made it 4 times faster and allowed rendering thousands of annotations.
- Documented and implemented best practices for the engineering team, which improved the code review process and performance of the application.
- Building an app for converting PDF documents into HTML and appropriate web viewer with annotating tooling.
- Conducted frontend interviews (JS, Browser Performance, CS).

Software TechLead

CCDS / Nezaboodka | Oct 2019 → May 2020

TypeScript React MobX Cornerstone.js Material-UI DICOM Scrum / Agile

 Built a modern web-based Viewer that visualized output of AI Models. The Viewer enabled many research centers to efficiently validate and iteratively test their AI algorithms, and served as a reference implementation for the central viewer used by the Radiology Department at MGH/BWH. Technical challenges addressed: virtualization and fast rendering of tens of thousands MRI images, maintaining compatibility with various medical standards (DICOM, DICOM-SEG, DICOM-SR)

- With a team of backend developers we built from scratch a web hub, used for loading, processing and viewing hundreds of medical studies which was successfully used by ML engineers.
- Took responsibilities for frontend provisioning in the company.

Senior Software Engineer

MintData | Aug 2016 → Mar 2018

TypeScript React MobX WebSocket MobX State Tree

- Participated in building a low-code development platform (LCDP) for creating and delivering real-time web applications. The LCDP is made of a spreadsheet which is used to define application logic instead of code, a surface to define the visual appearance, and behavioral links between the two.
- Designed a GUI builder which provides possibilities to create modern web interfaces without experience in HTML and CSS.
- Implemented synchronization layer for real-time editing in the GUI builder across multiple devices.
- Helped the company to hire new engineers. Conducted technical interviews with potential candidates.

Lead Software Developer

Nexus / CTDEV | Oct 2013 → Aug 2016

JavaScript AngularJS Highchars D3.js Node.js Scrum / Agile

- Participated in building and delivering fintech news portal based on modern custom recommendation engine.
- Designed variety of different data visualization libraries for rendering charts, graphs, maps.
- Developed custom gulp/grunt plugins for complex build system.
- Conducted technical interviews with potential candidates.

Senior Software Engineer

SoftSwiss | Apr 2018 → Oct 2019

TypeScript PixiJS WebGL React MobX Node.js styled-components Scrum / Agile

- Developed a modern game engine for multi-platform 2D games.
- Did a lot of performance optimization for smooth animation in games on low-end mobile devices.
- Implemented server-side scripts for processing images and audio.
- Interviewed new frontend candidates.

Senior Software Developer

EPAM Systems | Dec 2010 → Sep 2013

- C# .NET jQuery Angular.JS Scrum / Agile
- Participated in development of a platform for publishing financial apps.
- Developed web apps for the platform (time series data charts, market/exchange data viewers etc.).
- Built JavaScript API for third-party clients of the app.

BLOG ARTICLES

 How styled-components works: A deep dive under the hood Aug 2018

OPEN SOURCE

• Subtitle Translator

TypeScript Chrome Extensions API

Chrome Extension for fast subtitles translation on Netflix and other streaming services.

Babbler



A handy language switcher for macOS

• angular2-highcharts



HighchartsJS wrapper for Angular projects.

EDUCATION

Belarusian University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

Bachelor | Computer Science, Network Systems